{
    "id": "2415bb13499c4f82acf9eaea8f334d24",
    "title": "Subject Verb Agreement",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The council ………………….. chosen its chairman.",
            "description": " A collective noun takes a singular verb when the collection is thought of as a whole.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "4fad8a7cccd34bbb84a292bfcd94b6fe"
        },
        {
            "question": "The majority ……………… against the verdict.",
            "description": " A collective noun takes a singular verb when the collection is thought of as a whole.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e7db1f3e72a84f0f85bc49fb76591745"
        },
        {
            "question": "The wages of sin …………………… death.",
            "description": "Some verbs are plural in form, but singular in number. Wages is one of them.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ba8aa38b08c4414388907d8c2697a1f5"
        },
        {
            "question": "Each of the sisters ……………………. pretty.",
            "description": "We use a singular verb after each.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "06133e8cbdea4d5086232ecc834aafdb"
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither of the men ………………… able to solve the puzzle.",
            "description": "We use a singular verb after either and neither.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ef98a60106a042e4a71f794b9eb1eef0"
        },
        {
            "question": "Justice as well as mercy …………… it.",
            "description": "When another noun is joined to a singular noun by as well as, the verb is singular in number.",
            "answers": [
                "permit",
                "permits"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "1d77c02c0b284a079b79aafe54804ee5"
        },
        {
            "question": "The quality of the mangoes …………….. not good.",
            "description": "Here we use a singular verb because the subject is the singular noun quality.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "54b21994c9344ec08ac20cbfabbc996a"
        },
        {
            "question": "John as well as his team mates ………………. praise.",
            "description": "When another noun is joined to a singular noun by as well as, the verb is singular in number.",
            "answers": [
                "deserve",
                "deserves"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "11d247f0c51043e592ee8059e110de4a"
        },
        {
            "question": "You, who ……………….. my friend, should stand by me.",
            "description": "The verb in the relative clause should agree with its antecedent in number and person.",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "06c968a4e95c4553812d7f5b293b85cc"
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither his father nor his mother ……………….. alive.",
            "description": "We use a singular verb after either and neither. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ab14df26065d422db628f8612940913a"
        },
        {
            "question": "The jury ………………… divided in their opinion.",
            "description": "A collective noun usually takes a singular verb but when the reference is to the members of the group, it sometimes takes a plural verb. ",
            "answers": [
                "are",
                "is",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "44af3448c7b94c8b8a09528cc21f74fb"
        },
        {
            "question": "I, who ……………….. your friend, will guard your interests.",
            "description": "The verb in the relative clause should agree with its antecedent in number and person.",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "are",
                "is"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "91b0eec89598451cbd81b330025e1a89"
        }
    ]
}